Guide to the Veranus A. Moore Papers, 1836-1958
Moore, Veranus A. papers, 1836-1958
- Series VIII. Photographs
  - Miscellaneous Family and Friends - Negatives (Box 43, Folder 5)
Dugger, J.F. and W.F. Ward. "Experiments in beef production in Alabama." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 103, 27 Feb 1908.
E
Eager, J. M. "Yellow fever in France, Italy, Great Britain, and Austria, and Bibliography of Yellow Fever in Europe." United States Treasury Department, Marine-Hospital Service, Yellow Fever Institute Bulletin No. 8, May 1902.
Eber A. "Feststellung einheitlicher grundsatze fur die Beurteilung der Tuberkulinreaktion beim Rinde." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Eccles, R.G. "Darwinism and Diabetes."
Egan, James A. "Facts and fallacies concerning interstate reciprocity in medical licenses." A paper read by invitation, before the Illinois State Medical Society at Springfield, 17 May 1906.
Ernest, L.B. and Elmer Lash. "Tuberculin testing of livestock." United States Department of Agriculture, Circular, No. 249, December 1922.
Ernst, Harold C. "Progress of Medicine." An oration delivered before the Norfolf District Medical Socity at the Celebratin of the Semi-Centennial of its organization, 8 May 1900.
Evans, Alice C. "Studies on brucella (alkaligenes) melitensis." Treasury Department United States Public Health Service, Hygenic Laboratory Bulletin, August 1925.
Evans, Walter C. "Copper supnate and germination: treatment of seed with copper sulpahte to prevent the attacks of fungi." U.S. Department of Agriculture Division of Vegetable and Physiology and Pathology, Bulletin No. 10, 1896.
Exelby, Paul A. "An analysis of the results of treatment of caes of type II arthritis in the Sanford clinic." Reprinted from the Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, September 1930.
F
Fairchild, D.G. "Bodeaux Mixture as fungicide." U.S. Department of Agriculture Division of Vegetable Pathology, 1894.
______. "Experiments in preventing leaf diseases of nursery stock in Western New York." Reprinted form the Journal of Mycology, 1891.
Farrand, Livingston. "Health demonstrations in the United States." Reprinted from the American Journal of Public Health, February 1927.
Field, George W. "Notes on the mortality of incubator chicks." Agricultural Experiment Station of the Rhode Island College of Agriculture and Mechanic Arts, Bulletin No. 61, December 1899.
Finlay, Carlos Jr. "President's Address." Presented before the American Public Health Association Hava, Cuba, n.d.
Fischer, Paul. "Bovine tuberculosis." Experiment Station of the Kansas State Agricultural College, Bulletin No. 79, April 1898.
Fish, Pierre A. "The brain." Extracted from The Fur Seals and Fur Seal Islands of the North Pacific Ocean, Part III, 1899.
______. "Brain preservation with a resume of some old and new methods." Reprinted from the Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease, February 1894.
_______. "The central nervous system of desmognathus fusca. Reprinted from the Journal of Morphology, 1895.
_______. "The epithelium of the brain cavities." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Society of Microscopists, 1890.
_______. "The form and relations of the nerve cells and fibers in desmognathus fusca." Reprinted from Anatomischer Anzeiger, ca. 1894.
________. "Formalin for the preservation of brains." Journal of Comparative Neurology, July 1895.
_______. "The insidium of the callosum." Reprinted from the Journal of Comparative Neurology, June 1893.
______. "James Law." Reprinted from Cornell Veterinarian, July 1921.
________. "A new clearer for collodinized objects." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1893.
________. "Seventy years of veterinary service in the United States." Journal of the Amercian Veterinary Association, May 1929.
______. "The terminologyof the nerve cell." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, September 1984.
______. "The terminology of the nerve cell." Reprinted from Proceedings of Sixth Annual Session of Association of American Anatomists, 1894.
________. "Use of formalin in neurology." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1895.
Fisher, Irving and Emily F. Robbins. "Memorial relating to the conservation of human life as contemplated by bill (S.1) providing for a United States public-health service." Referred to the committee on public health and national quarantine and ordered to be printed, 5 April 1912.
Fitch, C.P. "Organisms morphologically resembling anthrax bacteria." Annual Report of the State Veterinary College, ca. 1905.
________. "A review of the principal methods used to standardize bacterin (bacterial vaccines)." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 13 March 1915.
Forbush, William Byron. "Amusement for Convalescent Children." New York State Department of Health, Circular No. 19, 1920.
Freiberg, Joseph A. "Arthritis-the allergic type." Reprinted from American Medicine, October 1930.
__________. "The allergic joint." Reprinted from the Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, August 1930.
__________. "Allergy as a Factor in the Production of proliferative arthritis." Reprinted from the Archives of Surgery, February 1929.
Frothingham, Langdon. "The Rapid Diagnosis of Rabies." Reprinted from The Journal of Medical Research, April 1906.
_________. "Impression preparations and the van gieson stain for negri bodies." Reprinted from the American Journal of Public Hygiene, February 1908.
Furtuna, M. "Etablissement de principes unifromes pour l'estimation de la reaction de la tuberculine et de la malleine. VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
G
Gage, Simon Henry. "Life-history of the vermilion-spotted newt." Reprinted from the American Naturalist, December 1891.
_______. "Marker for indicating the position of objects or parts of objects in microscopial preparations." Proceedings of the American Microscopial Society, 1894.
_______. "Notes on Historical methods including a brief consideration of the methods of pathlogical and vegetable histology." For the use of laboratory students in the anatomical department of the Cornell University, 1885-86.
_______. "Relation of the ureters and the great veins in the cat." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, 28-30 December 1898.
______. "The importance and the promise in the study of domestic animals." An address given to the American Association for the Advancement of Science, 21-26 August 1899.
_____. "Sketch of the life of John Henry Comstock, Professor Emeritus of Entomology in Cornell University." Reprinted with the permission of the National Council of Boy Scouts of American from Boy Scout Booklet, Insect Life, by J. Chester Bradley and E.L. Palmer.
Gage, Susanna Phelps. "A three weeks' human embryo with especial reference to the brain and the nephric system." Reprinted from the American Journal of Anatomy, 15 September 1905.
Galloway, B.T. "Report on the experiments made in 1891 in the treatment of plant diseases." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bulletin No. 3, 1892.
Geschickter, Charles F. "Laboratory aids in surgery of the bones and joints." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931.
Gibier, Paul. "Serumtheraphy in poisoning by the venom of snakes." Bulletin of the Pasteur Institute, 1897.
Gibson, H.B., S. Clavert and D.W. May. "Dietary studies at the universityof Missouri in 1895 and data relating to bread and meat consumption in Missouri." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Office of Experiment Stations, Bulletin No. 31, 1896.
Gilbert, Ruth and Marion B. Coleman. "Recent cases of undulant fever in New York state." Reprinted from the Journal of Infectious Diseases, October 1928.
Gill, Theodore. "Notes on the genus chonerhinus or xenopterus." Proceedings U.S. National Musuem, 1884.
________. "Notes on the genus hiatula of lacepee or tatoga of mitchill." Proceedings of U.S. National Musuem, 1884?
_______. "Notes on the tetraodontoida." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1892.
______. "On the genus gnathanacanthus of bleeker." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States Natoina Musuem, 1884?
Givens, Amos J. "Prevention of nervous and mental diseases through extension of medical inspection of schools." Read at the Stamford Medical Society, January 1911.
Gray, John W. "Classification and treatment of chronic arthritis." Journal of the Medical Society of New Jersey, May 1935.
______, Fendrick and Gowen. "Rheumatic fever and rheumatoid arthritis/ rheumatic fever and rheumatoid arthritis from the laboratory point of view." Texas State Journal of Medicine, July/ September 1932.
______ and Cecil H. Gowen. "The role of the streptococcus in arthritis deformans." American Journal of the Medical Sciences, November 1931.
Gruenberg, Benjamin C. "The chains of Prometheus." Reprinted from The Scientific Monthly, December 1927.
Guild, Harriet G. "The prognosis of acute glomerular nephritis in childhood." Reprinted form Bulletin of the Johns Hopkins Hospital, April 1931.
Greene, Carl H., Albert M. Snell and Waltman Walters, "Functional tests in the surgical diagnosis and treatment of diseases of the liver and bile ducts." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931.
Greenough, Robert B. "Treatment of malignant diseases with radium and x-ray." Reprinted from Surgery, Gynecology and Obstetrics, August 1929.
Gruber, Th. "Die Milch und deren Behandlung mit besondere Rucksicht auf die Reform des melkens, entsprechend den hyienishen anforderungen." VIII Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
H
Hagan, W.A. and J. Traum. "Studies in intradermal tuberculin." Cornell Veterinarian, April 1924.
Hale, Frank E. and Thomas W. Melia. "ABSTRACT; Studies on inibition, attenuation and rejuvenation of B. coli."
Haden, Russell, L. "Blood chemistry and the gastrointestinal tract." Reprinted from The Journal of Laboratory and Clinical Medicine, May 1931.
Harding, H.A., Geo. A. Smith and V.A. Moore. "A healthy herd from a tuberculous herd." New York Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 77, April 1906.
_______. "Effect of temperature of pasteurization on the creaming ability of milk." University of Illinois Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 237, December 1921.
______and L.L Van Slyke. "Chloroform as an aid in the study of milk enzymes." New York Agricultural Experiment Station, Technical Bulletin No. 6, December 1907.
_____and J.K. Wilson. "A study of the udder flora of cows." Technical Bulletin No. 27, n.d.
Haring, C.M., W.A. Sawyer and D.N. Morgan. "Bovine tuberculosis investigations." Reprinted from the Proceedings of the Forty-sixth Annual Convention of the American Veterinary Medical Association, 1909.
________and Ralph M. Bell. "The intradermal test for tuberculosis in cattle and hogs." College of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station, Berkeley, California, Bulletin No. 23, March 1914.
Hardenbergh, J.B. and Fred Boerner Jr. "Vaccinations against hemorrhagic septicemia, no. 2." Reprinted from The Journal of American Veterinary Medicine, March 1917.
Hassall, Albert and C.W. Stiles. "Strongylus rubidus, a new species of nematode, parasitic in pigs." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Medicine and Veterinary Archives, April 1892.
Hasseltine, H.E. "Current studies of undulant fever." Reprinted from the Public Health Reports, 12 July 1929.
Hatcher, Robert A. "The work of the council on pharmacy and chemistry." Reprinted from The American Medical Asssociation Journal, 4 November 1916.
Heard, Dwight B. "Public grazing lands: the range homestead." Reprinted from The American Review of Reviews, September 1915.
Henkel, Alice. "Wild Medicinal plants of the United States." U.S. Department of Agricuture Bureau of Plant Industry, Bulletin No. 89, 1906.
Hewitt, Charles N. "Infectious Diseases of hogs: a paper describing some of these diseases as they appear in swine." State Board of Health in Minnesota, 1894.
Hickman, Richard W. "Description and treatment of scabies in cattle." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 40, 1902.
Hill, R.L. "The physical curd character of milk and its relationship to the digestibility of food value of milk for infants." Utah Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 207, June 1928.
Hilton, William A. "The morphology and development of intestinal folds and villi in vertebrates." Reprinted form The American Journal of Anatomy, 15 September 1902.
Hoard, W.D. "Responsibility of the veterinarian to the dairyman [ delivered at the New York State Veterinary College, 15 December 1909]." 1909.
Hoffman. "Treatment of tuberculosis by means of glandulen: a specific organic remedy." ca. 1899.
Holden, Edgar and John Gray. "adamantinoma of the tibia." Journal of Bone and Joint Surgery, April 1934.
Holmes, Edmund W. "The defects of our present methods of teaching anatomy in our medical schools." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Association of American Anatomists, 28-30 December 1898.
Hopkins, Grant Sherman. "On the enteron of American ganoids." Reprinted from Journal of Morphology, 1895.
_________. "The heart of some lungless salamanders." Reprinted from American Naturalist, 1 October1896.
__________. "Apparatus for illustrating the circulation of the lymph." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Micropathology Sociey, 1895.
Howard, George E. "Standard varieties of chickens." U.S. Department of Agriculture Farmers' Bulletin, No. 51, 1897.
Howe, William A. "Mutual helpfulness in the conservation of public health." Read before the New York State Medical Society, 19 April 1911.
Huddleson, I. Forest. "A further epidemiological study of undulant fever in Michigan." Reprinted from Symposium on Undulant Fever, October 1928.
_________. "The differentiation of the species of the genus brucella." Reprinted from Symposium on Undulant Fever, October 1928.
__________. "The pathogenicity of the species of the genus brucella for monkeys." Reprinted from The Journal of Infectious Diseases, October 1929.
________. "The differentiation of the species of the genus brucella." Agricultural Experiment Station, Michigan State College of Agriculture and Applied Science, Technical Bulletin, No. 100, August 1929.
________. "The comparative pathogenicity of several strains of bacterium abortus (bang)." Agricultural Experiment Station, Michigan Agricultural College, Technical Bulletin, No. 55, March 1922.
_________. "Rapid macroscopic agglutination for the serum diagnosis of bang's abortion disease." Reprinted from The Journal of Infectious Diseases, March 1928.
Hughes, E.H. "The feeding value of raisins and dairy by-products for growing and fattening swine." University of California College of Agriculture Agricultural Experiment Station, Berkeley, California, Bulletin No. 440, November 1927.
I
Iles, George. "electricity uncovers a law of evolution." July 1909.
Istvan, Cselko. "A lefolozott tej mint takarmany kulonos tekintettel a suldohizlalasra." VIII. Nemzetkozi allatorvosi kongresszu Budapesten, 1905.
J
Jackson, D.D. and T.C. Muer. "ABSTRACT; A medium for the determination of gas forming bacteria in water and sewage."
Janos, Tatray. "Egyseges elvek megallapitasa a malleinreactio elbiralasara." VIII. Nemzetkozi allatorvosi kongresszu Budapesten, 1905.
Joest, E. "Bekampfung der schweineseuche und schweinepest; schutzimpfungen." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Johannsen, Oskar, A. "Tests of water by bacterial inoculaton." Reprinted from American Medicine, February 1907.
Jones, F.S. "Fatal Septicemia or bacillary white diarrhea in young chickens." Annual Report of the State Veterinary College, n.d.
__________. "An outbreak of an acute disease in adult fowls, due to bact pullorum." Journal of Medical Research, March 1913.
Jong, D.A. "Bekampfung der tuberkulose der Haustiere." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Jong, D.A. "Rapports entre la tuberculose de l'homme, du gros betail, de la volaille, et d'autres animaus dometiques (notamment du chien)." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinarie Budapest, 1905.
Jordan, David Star. "Observations on fur seals of the pribilof islands." A preliminary report, 1896.
Jordan, Edwin O. "The self-purification of streams." The Decennial Publications, 1903.
K
Kelser, R.A. and R.W. Mohri." Comparative germicidal tests of mercurochrome and tincture of iodine." Journal of the Amercian Veterinary Medical Association, January 1932.
King, Merrill J. and W.H. Park. "Effect of Calmett's BCG vaccine on experimental animals." American Journal of Public Health, February 1929.
Kingsbury, Benjamin F. "The histoloical structures of the enteron of nectars maculatus." Reprinted from Proceedings of the American Microscopical Society, 1894.
__________. "The structure and morphology of the oblongata in fishes." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, April 1897.
__________. "The encephalic evanginations in ganoids." Reprinted from The Journal of Comparative Neurology, April 1897.
__________. "The spermatogenesis of desmognathus fusca." Reprinted from The American Journal of Anatomy, 28 February 1902.
Kjerrulf, Bericht von. "Verfalschung des fleisches und der fleischprodukte und die zu deren nachweise dieneden neueren untersuchungmethoden." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicher Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Kanavel, Allen B. "The treatment of infected wounds on surgical service." Reprinted from Bulletin of the American College of Surgeons, 3 September 1930.
Kirby-Smith, J.L. and G.F. White. "Creeping Eruption." Reprinted from The Archives of Dermatology and Syphilogy, February 1926.
Kirkbride, Mary B. "Hemolytic streptococcus carriers: their relation to the spread of scarlet fever." Reprinted from The Journal of American Medical Associations, 22 October 1927.
Kozlowski, Anthony. "Effect of ricinoleated vaccine of the hemolytic streptococcus (scarlet fever) on animals." Journal of Immunology, March1928.
L
Laidlaw, Frank W. "Nuisances: Duties and Powers of Health Officers and Boards of Health." New York State Department of Health., n.d.
Lambert, James. "The germ theory of disease." A paper read before the Irish Central Veterinary Medical Society, 15 April 1883.
Lane, C.B. "The milking machine as a factor in dairying: a preliminary report." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 92, 1907.
Langworthy, C.F. "Fish as Food." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 85, 1898.
__________. "Eggs and their uses as food." U.S. Department of Agriculture, Farmers' Bulletin No. 128, 1901.
Law, James. "Tuberculosis in relation to animal industry and public health." Cornell University Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 65, April 1894.
Leclainche, M.E. "La Serotherapie des maladies infectieuses des animaux domestiqus." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
Lignieres, J. "les maladies tropicales des animaux domestiques." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
________. "La serotherapie des maladies infectieuses chez les animaux domestiques." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
Lienaux, E. "Le cancer chez les animaux domestiques." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinaire a Budapest, 1905.
Linch, Charles. "Private practitioners in tuberculosis eradication." Cornell Veterinarian, July 1923.
Linstow, Gottingen von. "Die durch tierische parasiten erzeugten tox ischen stoffe." VIII Congres International de Medecine Veterinaire, Budapest, 1905.
Loeffler, Bericht von. "Die Schutzimpfung gegen die maul-und klauenseuche." VIII Internationaler tierarzlicher congress in Budapest, 1905.
Logan, Walter S. "Laissez Faire." Address delivered before the post-graduate class of the Georgetown, D.C., Law School, 26 April 1902.
Lorenz, "Uber die art infection bei der tuberkulose der haustiere." VIII. Internationaler tierarzlicher congress in Budapest 1905.
Lucas, Frederic A. "Notes on the anatomy and affinities of the coerebidae and other American birds." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Museum, 1894.
Lucas, Frederic A. "Notes on the preparation of rough skeletons." Part C of Buletin of the United States National Museum, 1891.
________. "On the structure of the tongue in humming birds." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1891.
Lucker, John T. "A new genus and new species of trematode worms of the family plagiorchiidaie." Reprinted from Proceedings of the United States National Musuem, 1931.
Lumsedn, L.L. "Extent of rural health service in the United States, 1923-1927." Public Health Report, 29 April 1927.
Lusk, Graham. "Fundamental Requirements of energy for proper nutrition." Reprinted from The Journal of American Medical Associations, 23 March 1918. __________. "Pastuer, the man." Reprinted from Science, 2 February 1923.
Lydston, Frank G. "The Russianizing of Americnan Medicine and the Medical Dreyfus." From a meeting of the Mississippi Valley Medical Association, 10 November 1909.
M
Mack, W.B. "The etiology and morbid anatomy of diptheria in chickens" Reprinted form the American Veterinary Review, January 1905.
__________and Edward Records. "The control of contagious epithelioma in chickens by vaccination." Agricultural Experiment Station the University of Nevada, Bulletin No. 82, June 1915.
MacDonald, Arthur. "Ethics as applied to criminology." Reprinted from The Journal of Mental Sciences, January 1891.
Malkmus, "Ausdehnung der Verkehrsbeschrankungen beim auftreten der nicht unmittelbar kontagosen infektionskrankheiten namentlich des milzbrandes." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicer Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Malm, Med. "Feststellung einheitlicher Grundsatze fer die beurteilung der tuberculin und mallein-reaktion." VIII. Internationaler Tierarzlicer Kongress in Budapest, 1905.
Martel, M.H. "Falsifications de la viande et des produits carnes alimentaires nouvaux moyens d'analyse." VIII. Congres International de medecine veterinarire a Budapest, 1905.
Mason, William. "Pure food legislation." A speech, 2 May 1900.
Master, Arthur, M. "Low-voltage t waves in the electrocardiogram." Reprinted from the American Journal of Medical Sciences, February 1931.
________. "Meningococcemia with Endocarditis." Reprinted from The Journal of the American Medical Association, 17 January 1931.
________ and A. Romanoff. "Electrocardiographic changes in pneumonia." Reprinted from Proceedings of the Society of Experimental Biology and Medicine, 1930.
May, Charles. "Method in Medical Study." Reprinted from The New York Medical Journal, 18 September 1886
Mayo, N. S. "Cattle Poinsoning by Nitrate of Potash." Experiment Station of the Kansas State Agricultural College, Bulletin No. 49, May 1895.
________. "Texas itch." Experiment Station of the Kansas State Agricultural College, No. 69, June 1897.
Mazer, Charles and A.J. Ziserman. "The present status of female sex hormone therapy." Reprinted from Medical Journal and Record, 6 January 1932.
McBryde, C.N. "The germicidal value of liquor cresolis compositus (u.s.p.)." U.S. Department of Agriculture Bureau of Animal Industry, Bulletin No. 100, 31 May 1907.
McAlister, Harold. "Dairy breed comparisons VII: official butter records of breeds." Holstein-Friesian Association of America pamphlet, 1917.
McCord, Clinton P. "Physical and mental condition of delinquent boys." Reprinted from Albany Medical Annals, April 1919.
McCulloch, Charles. "The teeth of the horse as affected by age, part I." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 116, September 1900.
__________. "The teeth of the horse as affected by age, part II." Virginia Agricultural Experiment Station, Bulletin No. 116, September 1900.